<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>assumednormal</title>
    <link>https://www.assumednormal.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on assumednormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.assumednormal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictor Variance Reduces Standard Error of Slopes</title>
      <link>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/predictor-variance-reduces-standard-error-of-slopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/predictor-variance-reduces-standard-error-of-slopes/</guid>
      <description>A common solution to moderate degradation in marketing or risk models is to re-fit the same model on newer vintages. This approach has at least two benefits.
 Modelers can open the original model fitting code, drop in the new data set, and be done with the re-fit in a few hours. The original model would have gone through a comprehensive review of methodology, performance, and implementation. Having followed the same methodology, all that would be left to review is performance and implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finite Population Correction</title>
      <link>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/finite-population-correction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/finite-population-correction/</guid>
      <description>When sampling with replacement from finite populations, we have to change how we think about sampling from the larger population. Now what we measure on each sampled individual is fixed: a person&amp;rsquo;s height and weight, a family&amp;rsquo;s annual income, etc. What is considered random is whether or not each individual is selected for inclusion in the sample.
Suppose there are $N$ individuals in a population. We take a sample of $n$ individuals without replacement and measure their heights, $h_i$, $i=1,\ldots,n$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negative R-Squared</title>
      <link>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/negative-r-squared/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.assumednormal.com/post/negative-r-squared/</guid>
      <description>The coefficient of determination is typically written as $\textrm{R}^2=1-\textrm{SS}_{\textrm{res}}/\textrm{SS}_{\textrm{tot}}$. But there are a few assumptions behind the simple formula that lead to nonsensical results when violated.
Suppose you fit a simple linear regression on some data set. If the independent and dependent variables are not proportional, the intercept will necessarily be non-zero. If you force the intercept to zero, the $\textrm{R}^2$ of the fitted line may be less than zero.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>